

2 Profile

Passionate Software Engineer with 2.8+ years of experience. A creative thinker and a problem solver, delivering products that are functional and user-friendly. Knowledgeable in back-end and front-end development. Proficient in an assortment of technologies, including Heroku, AWS, GitHub, BitBucket, Braintree, GoDaddy, and NeverBoucne. Able to effectively self-manage during independent or remote projects, as well as collaborate in a team setting. Experienced in agile development via the usage of Kanban boards.

Employment History

Lead Developer at SafetySpot Inc.

January 2018 - Present

- Effectively communicate and translate client requirements into application designs and systems requirements.
- Redesigned blog's site by creating a full mobile responsive design for better readability and deliverance of information.
- Improved site's accessibility by 60% by implementing ARIA attributes
- Increased ability to add data by creating duplicate column feature.
- Improved data upload by creating a self-checking CSV file upload feature.
- Implemented invoice receipt feature connecting to Braintree.
- Improved stack's ability to refactor by updating and maintaining test suite.
- Manage front-end and back-end development as well as code integration.

Full Stack Developer at SafetySpot Inc.

February 2017 – December 2017

- Provided effective troubleshooting and remediation for applications stack.
- Created social media presence and developed feature to easily share content from web application to different social media outlets.
- 100% Development of user mentioning (tagging) in comments utilizing AJAX (JSON) and React.js.
- 95% Development of terms of conditions page & agreement feature.
- 95% Development of adding pictures to assets (AWS) to improve U|X.
- 90% Development of Safety Spot's blog to create user reachability.
- 90% Development of a log for daily activities.
- 85% Development of API for mobile app connectivity.

Education

M.S. in Project Management, Universidad Tecnológica Centroamericana, Tegucigalpa

August 2012 - September 2014

B.S. in Civil Engineering, University of New Orleans, New Orleans

August 2006 – December 2010

Details

Tegucigalpa, Honduras, 95009542

jocvegar@gmail.com

Links

Online CV GitHub

Skills

Ruby on Rails

HTML & CSS

JavaScript

Heroku

Git

Markdown

AWS

React.js

WordPress

Braintree

Hobbies

Family and friends, exploring latest technology advancements, coding practice applications, cooking, gardening and skipping rope.

Languages

Spanish

English